Guide to the Administrative Papers of the President George Bugliarello RG.006
Poly Archives at the Bern Dibner Library of Science and Technology, NYU Libraries
- Series V: Speeches & Symposia, 9
  - Subseries B: Symposia, 2081
    - "Education of the Inventor" - Annual Meeting of the American Society of Engineering Education - Knoxville, Tennessee, 1976 June 16; 5718 (Box 41, Folder 10)
- Series VI: Publications & Manuscripts, 12
  This series contains published books and published and unpublished articles written and edited by George Bugliarello as well as his handwritten notes and research material he used for various publications. Subseries f: Books contains autographed copies of books by other authors addressed to George Bugliarello and Gioia Marconi Braga, daughter of Guglielmo Marconi, founder of the Marconi International Fellowship Foundation.
  The publications have been assigned a number based on a numbering system adopted by the President's office to keep track of publications. Please see Box 42 / Folder 1 "List of Publications" for a complete list of George Bugliarello's publications compiled in October 2011.
  This series is arranged by document type. The publications and reports and newspaper articles are arranged according to the publication number assigned by the donor and are otherwise ordered chronologically.
  - subseries A: Publications and Reports, 1715
    - List of Publications, 1953-1985; 1717 (Box 41, Folder 11)
    - Clipping Book - M1-M17, 1970-1979; 1718 (Box 41, Folder 12)
    - M1 – "Society, Technology and the College of Engineering", 1970 January; 1719 (Box 41, Folder 13)
    - M2 – "On Meta-Technology", 1970 October; 1720 (Box 41, Folder 14)
    - M3 - "On the State of the College and Other Matters" (University of Illinois, Chicago Circle), 1970 December; 1721 (Box 41, Folder 15)
    - M5 – "The Professional School and Chicago Circle", 1972 May 12; 1722 (Box 41, Folder 16)
    - M6 – "Some World Views of Technology", 1974 December; 1723 (Box 41, Folder 17)
    - M7 – "Technology, the University and the Community: A Delicate Balance", 1975 March 13; 1724 (Box 41, Folder 18)
    - M8 – "Industry-University Interaction is Good For Business", 1975 January 15; 1725 (Box 41, Folder 19)
    - M9 – "The Biosoma: The Coming Together of Biological Organisms, Social Organizations and Machines", 1975 March 6; 1726 (Box 41, Folder 20)
    - M10 – "New York or New Byzantium?", 1975 June 2; 1727 (Box 41, Folder 21)
    - M12 - "Technology and the Corporation" – Lord Corporation, 1976 April 23; 1728 (Box 41, Folder 22)
    - M13 - "Introduction--Part I. The Brooklyn Bridge in Perspective: Its Building and Its Builders", 1984; 1729 (Box 41, Folder 23)
    - M15 – "Il Parco Tecnologico: Note Sulle Risorse, Competenze Ed Organizzazione", 1991; 1730 (Box 41, Folder 24)
    - T1 - "Technology Units in City Government", 1975 June 16; 1731 (Box 41, Folder 25)
    - T3 - Testimony at Joint Hearing of Senate & Assembly Higher Education Committees, 1975 December 3; 1732 (Box 41, Folder 26)
    - T4 - Statement to Board of Estimate on Jay St. Fire House, 1975 December 4; 1733 (Box 41, Folder 27)
    - T5 - Long Island as the Seri Site, 1975 December 19; 1734 (Box 41, Folder 28)
    - #3 – "La Resistenza al Moto Accelerato di Sfere in Acqua", 1956 February; 1735 (Box 41, Folder 29)
    - #4 – "Pertinent Factors in Flow Research on Dilute Fiber Suspensions", 1957 June; 1736 (Box 41, Folder 30)
    - #6 – "Effects of Fibers on Velocity Distribution, Turbulence and Flow Resistance of Dilute Suspensions", 1958 October; 1737 (Box 41, Folder 31)
    - #7 – "Impianti Elioelettrici", 1958; 1738 (Box 41, Folder 32)
    - #8 – "A Particular Non-Newtonian Flow-- Dilute Fiber Suspension", 1959 July; 1739 (Box 41, Folder 33)
    - #10 – "Fluid Mechanics – Its Scope and Challenge", 1961 May; 1740 (Box 41, Folder 34)
    - #12 – "The Water Resources Problem in Haiti--A Case for the Interdisciplinary Approach", 1962; 1741 (Box 41, Folder 35)
    - #13 – "Electronic Computer Use in Scoping Power Projects", 1961 July; 1742 (Box 41, Folder 36)
    - #14 – "Toward a Computer Language for Hydraulic Engineering", 1961; 1743 (Box 41, Folder 37)
    - #15 – "Basic Data for Dilute Fiber Sus¬pension in Uniform Flow with Shear", 1961 July; 1744 (Box 41, Folder 38)
    - #16 – "Rheological Models and Laminar Shear Flow of Fiber Suspensions", 1961 December; 1745 (Box 41, Folder 39)
    - #17 – "I. Moti Non-Newtonian nell'Ingegneria Idraulica (Non-Newtonian Flows in Hydraulic Engineering)", 1962; 1746 (Box 41, Folder 40)
    - #18 – "Une Revue des Resources Hydrauliques en Haiti" (A Review of the Hydraulic Resources of Haiti), 1962 April; 1747 (Box 41, Folder 41)
    - #19 – "High-speed Microcinematographic Studies of Blood Flow in Vitro", 1962; 1748 (Box 41, Folder 42)
    - #20 – "Detailed Characteristics of the Flow of Blood In Vitro", 1963; 1749 (Box 41, Folder 43)
    - #21 – "Some Considerations of the Analysis and Design of Hydraulic Machinery for Non-Newtonian Fluids", 1963; 1756 (Box 41, Folder 44)
    - #22 – "The Rule of Flood Plains in the Correlation Between Flood Predictions and Dam Design", 1963; 1757 (Box 41, Folder 45)
    - #23 - "Phase Separation in Suspensions Flowing Through Bifurcations: A Simplified Hemodynamic Model", 1964 January 31; 4640 (Box 41, Folder 46)
    - #24 – "Flow of Clay-Water Suspensions", 1964; 1758 (Box 41, Folder 47)
    - #25 – "Man-Machine Communication in Civil Engineering", 1964; 1759 (Box 41, Folder 48)
    - #26 – "The Mechanism of Phase Separation at Bifurications", 1964; 1760 (Box 41, Folder 49)
    - #27 – "Random Walk Study of Convective Diffusion", 1964 August; 1761 (Box 41, Folder 50)
    - #28 – "The Profile Viscosity and Other Characteristics of Blood Flow", 1965; 1762 (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - #29 – "Bio-Engineering As a New Dialogue", 1965; 1763 (Box 42, Folder 2)
    - #30 – "Exploratory Studies on the Stochastic Simulation of Outfall Flows", 1965; 1764 (Box 42, Folder 3)
    - #31 – "Hospitals", 1965; 1765 (Box 42, Folder 4)
    - #32 – "Microcirculation Hemodynamics and other Bio Flow Problems", 1965 April; 1766 (Box 42, Folder 5)
    - #33 – "Mathematical Representation of an Urban Flood Plan", 1965 March; 1767 (Box 42, Folder 6)
    - #34 – "Non-Newtonian Flows", 1965 August; 1768 (Box 42, Folder 7)
    - #35 – "A Simplified Model of the Flow in the Plasmatic Gaps of the Smaller Circulatory Vessels", 1965; 1769 (Box 42, Folder 8)
    - #36 – "An Engineering Oriented View of Biological Flows", 1966 October 12-14; 1770 (Box 42, Folder 9)
    - #37 – "Engineering Implications of Biological Flow Process", 1966; 1771 (Box 42, Folder 10)
    - #39 – "Concentration Redistribution Phenomena in the Shear Flow of Monolayers of Suspended Particles", 1966; 1772 (Box 42, Folder 11)
    - #40 – "Hydro – A Computer Language for Water Resources Engineering", 1966 November; 1773 (Box 42, Folder 12)
    - #41 – "Design Philosophy, Specifications, and Implications of Hydro", 1967; 1774 (Box 42, Folder 13)
    - #42 – "Random Walk Study of Convective Division", 1964 August; 1775 (Box 42, Folder 14)
    - #43 – "Programming Needs in the Water Resources Field and the Role of a Problem Oriented Language", 1966 November; 1776 (Box 42, Folder 15)
    - #44 – "Study of Convective Diffusion from Continuous Point Sources By a Random Walk Model", 1966; 1777 (Box 42, Folder 16)
    - #45 – "Model Studies of the Hydronamic Characteristics of an Erythrocyte", 1966; 1778 (Box 42, Folder 17)
    - #46 - "Stochastic Simulation of the Diffusion of Jets", 1967; 1779 (Box 42, Folder 18)
    - #63 - "A Stochastic Model of Convective Diffusion from a Continuous Source", 1969; 1780 (Box 42, Folder 19)
    - #70 - "An Introduction to the Stochastic Simulation of Flow Processes", 1966 September 7; 1781 (Box 42, Folder 20)
    - #85 – "Large Socio-Technological Systems: Human Conflict and Human Design", 1970; 1782 (Box 42, Folder 21)
    - #112 - "The New Phase in Engineering Education: Engineering and the New Liberal Education", 1973 February; 1783 (Box 42, Folder 22)
    - #115 - Socio-Technology: The Emergence of a New Ideology & A New Technology, 1973 May; 1784 (Box 42, Folder 23)
    - #131 – Biofluidmechanics, 1977 June; 1786 (Box 42, Folder 24)
    - #133 - "The Biosoma: The Coming Together of Man, Society and Machines", 1978 July; 1787 (Box 42, Folder 25)
    - #135 – "Expanding Your Research Capabilities", 1978 June 7; 1788 (Box 42, Folder 26)
    - #136 – "Perspectives in Biomechanics Research and Education for Next Decade", 1978 February; 1789 (Box 42, Folder 27)
    - #137 – "Blood Flow in Straight and Curved Capillary Glass Tubes", 1979; 1790 (Box 42, Folder 28)
    - #138 - "Engineering Education for the 21st Century, To Respond to the Needs of Space Systems Engineering", 1979; 1791 (Box 42, Folder 29)
    - #139 – "Technology & Society: It's Time to Wake up to the Problems", 1978 September 28-29; 1792 (Box 42, Folder 30)
    - #149 - "The Role of the University Assisting Industry in the Fulfillment of the National and Regional Needs", 1979; 1793 (Box 42, Folder 31)
    - #159 - "Development of Urban Research Parks", 1983; 1794 (Box 42, Folder 32)
    - #160 – "The Generation of Knowledge in Advanced Countries", 1984; 1795 (Box 42, Folder 33)
    - #175 - Technology in Society – "Editor's Note", 1984; 1796 (Box 42, Folder 34)
    - #187 - "Socio-Technology and Systems Analysis and Engineering", 1986; 1798 (Box 42, Folder 35)
    - #198 - "Toward Hyperintelligence", 1988 September; 1799 (Box 42, Folder 36)
    - #200 - "Technology & the Environment", 1989; 1800 (Box 42, Folder 37)
    - #206 – "Science and Technology in New York City for the 21st Century", 1989 December; 1801 (Box 42, Folder 38)
    - #214 - "Engineering & Its Social Function: A Current Assessment", 1990 October 3; 1802 (Box 42, Folder 39)
    - #217 - "New Trends in Research Management", 1991 April 17-19; 1803 (Box 42, Folder 40)
    - #223 – "How Long Will We Continue to Accept the Dismantling of our Industry?", 1992 January; 1804 (Box 42, Folder 41)
    - #227 - "The Ideal of Civil Engineering", 1994 July; 1805 (Box 42, Folder 42)
    - #229 - "Science at the Crossroads", 1993 February 25; 1806 (Box 42, Folder 43)
    - #231 - "Technology Transfer: A Socio-Technological Paradigm", 1994; 1807 (Box 42, Folder 44)
    - #232 - "Metrotech: An Urban University Industry Park", 1993 Spring; 1808 (Box 42, Folder 45)
    - #233 - "The Role of the University in Charting a Path for the Twenty-first Century", 1993 October; 1809 (Box 42, Folder 46)
    - #236 - "The Future of Bioengineering", 1994; 1810 (Box 42, Folder 47)
    - "Implications of the Energy Crisis for Engineering Education", 1974 June; 1811 (Box 42, Folder 48)
    - "C&EN Talks With Dr. George Bugliarello", 1974 June 3; 1812 (Box 42, Folder 49)
    - "Towards the Technological University", 1975 September 18; 1813 (Box 42, Folder 50)
    - "Social Technology: The Quest for Human Dignity and Machine Efficiency", 1977 July; 1814 (Box 42, Folder 51)
    - "Risk and Reliability – A Bio-Socio-Technological View", 1978; 1815 (Box 42, Folder 52)
    - "Technology and the Environment", 1985 October–1986 April; 1816 (Box 42, Folder 53)
    - "Institute of Imaging Sciences Five Year Plan", 1986; 1817 (Box 42, Folder 54)
    - "Physical and Information Sciences and Engineering", 1989; 1818 (Box 42, Folder 55)
    - "Rethinking America's Industry: Challenges for Industry, the Universities & National Policies", 1992 June 4; 1819 (Box 42, Folder 56)
    - The Quality – "La Creazione Dell' Universita…", 1993 January-March; 1820 (Box 42, Folder 57)
    - "Short Course on Security Management", 1993 March 29; 1821 (Box 42, Folder 58)
    - "L'Emergere Della Socio-Tecnologica", Undated; 1822 (Box 42, Folder 59)
    - "A Reflection on Art, Science & Technology", Undated; 1823 (Box 42, Folder 60)
    - "Report of the President's Commission on the Waste in Human Design", Undated; 1824 (Box 42, Folder 61)
    - "Synthesis in Engineering: The New Wave" – Notes, Undated; 1825 (Box 42, Folder 62)
    - "University-Industry Relation, Passion and Rationality", Undated; 1826 (Box 42, Folder 63)
  - Subseries B: Newspaper Articles, 1716
    - Clipping Book – N1-N12, 1975-1991; 1827 (Box 42, Folder 64)
    - N6 – New York Times – Flawed Tuition Plan, 1976 November 18; 1828 (Box 42, Folder 65)
    - N7 – Social Technology: The Quest for Human Dignity and Machine Efficiency, 1977 July; 1829 (Box 42, Folder 66)
    - N8 – Detroit Modeling Itself on the Electronics Industry, 1980 December 22; 1830 (Box 42, Folder 67)
    - N1, N2, N3, N9, N10, 1975-1985; 1831 (Box 42, Folder 68)
    - N18 - "Debate Over Academie's Ties with Industry", 1992 October 21; 1832 (Box 42, Folder 69)
  - Subseries C: Research, 1833
    - Civil Engineering Education, 1992-1994; 1834 (Box 42, Folder 70)
    - Cornell Waste Management, 1989; 1835 (Box 42, Folder 71)
    - Earthquake Preparation, 1989-1990; 1836 (Box 42, Folder 72)
    - "Science & Technology in Government" – Outline, Undated; 1837 (Box 42, Folder 73)
  - Subseries D: Notes, 1695
    - Miscellaneous, 1979-1993; 1838 (Box 42, Folder 74)
    - Handwritten Notes, Undated; 1839 (Box 42, Folder 75)
    - Handwritten Notes, Undated; 1840 (Box 42, Folder 76)
    - Handwritten Notes, 1993?; 1841 (Box 42, Folder 77)
  - Subseries E: Biosoma, 2093
    Scope and Content note
    Biosoma, a term coined by George Bugliarello, refers to the interaction between biology, society and machines. This subseries contains manuscripts, drafts, and notes relating to George Bugliarello's research and promotion of the Biosoma paradigm.
    - Biosoma - Draft, 1993 November 30; 2094 (Box 42, Folder 78)
    - Biosoma - Draft, Editorial Comments, Undated; 2095 (Box 43, Folder 1)
    - Biosoma: The New Genesis - Correspondence & Edits, 1982; 2096 (Box 43, Folder 2)
    - Biosoma: The New Genesis - Correspondence & Edits, 1982; 2097 (Box 43, Folder 3)
    - Biosoma Figures - Revised, 1979 April; 2098 (Box 43, Folder 4)
    - Biosoma Figures - Revised, 1979 May; 2099 (Box 43, Folder 5)
    - Biosoma - Manuscripts - 1, 1979; 2100 (Box 43, Folder 6)
    - Biosoma - Manuscripts - 2, 1979; 2101 (Box 43, Folder 7)
  - Subseries F: Books, 5788
    - i. Written and Edited by George Bugliarello, 5807
      - Bugliarello, G. (Ed.) Bioengineering, An Engineering View. San Francisco: San Francisco Press, 1968. 2 copies., 5789 (Volume 1)
      - Bugliarello, G. and F. J. Gunther, Computer Systems and Water Resources. Amsterdam: Elsevier Scientific Publishing Company, 1974., 5790 (Volume 2)
      - Bugliarello, G. and H.A. Simon, Technology, The Community and The University. Pergamon Press, 1976., 5791 (Volume 3)
      - Bugliarello, G. and D. Doner (Eds.) The History and Philosophy of Technology. Chicago: University of Illinois Press, 1979. 2 copies., 5792 (Volume 4)
      - Bugliarello, G. (Ed), Urban Security - Engineering the Protection of Our Cities, Polytechnic University, 2003., 5793 (Volume 5)
    - ii. Autographed copies, 5794
      - Bracewell, Ronald N. The Galactic Club: Intelligent Life in Outerspace. San Francisco: San Francisco Book Company, Inc. 1976. Autographed to Gioia Marconi Braga., 5795 (Volume 6)
      - Killian, James R. Jr. Sputnik, Scientists, and Eisenhower: A Memoir of the First Special Assistant to the President of Science and Technology. Massachusetts: The MIT Press. 1977. Autographed to Gioia Marconi Braga., 5796 (Volume 7)
      - Dibner, Bern. Immortals of Science: Alessandro Volta and the Electric Battery. New York: Franklin Watts, Inc. 1983. Autographed to Gioia Marconi Braga., 5797 (Volume 8)
      - Carassa, Francesco. Il Sogno Dei Gigahertz. Rome: Sarin. 1985. Autographed to George Bugliarello., 5808 (Volume 9)
      - Jacobs, Joseph. The Anatomy of an Entrepreneur: Family, Culture and Ethics. San Francisco: ICS Press. 1991. Autographed to George Bugliarello., 5798 (Volume 10)
      - Lucky, Robert W. Lucky Strikes...again. New York: IEEE Press. 1993. Autographed to Gioia Marconi Braga., 5799 (Volume 11)
    - iii. George Bugliarello Publications Bound Volumes, 5800
      - Volume 2, Nos. 12-41, 1962-1967; 5801 (Volume 12)
      - Volume 4, Nos. 67-82, 1968-1969; 5802 (Volume 13)
      - Volume 5, Nos. 83-103, 1969-1971; 5803 (Volume 14)
      - Volume 7, Nos. 123-150, 1975-1981; 5804 (Volume 15)
      - Volume 8, Nos. 151-176, 1980-1985; 5805 (Volume 16)
      - Volume 9, Nos. 177-219, 1984-1992; 5806 (Volume 17)
- Series VII: Correspondence, 1693
  This series contains mostly miscellaneous correspondence as well as a collection of business cards collected by George Bugliarello. Frequent correspondents have been separated and given their own folders.
  This series is arranged alphabetically by the last name of the correspondent. The contents of each folder are arranged chronologically.
  - Brademas, John, 1970-1974; 7053 (Box 43, Folder 8)
  - Burkart, Joe, 1980 November-1982 February; 1973 (Box 43, Folder 9)
  - Cardwell, Vivian, undated; 7054 (Box 43, Folder 10)
  - Conti, Jim, 1979 November-1983 October; 1974 (Box 43, Folder 11)
  - Donaruma, Guy, 1980 November–1981 December; 1975 (Box 43, Folder 12)
  - Donaruma, Guy, 1982 December-1983 September; 1976 (Box 43, Folder 13)
  - Koch, Ed, 1985-1998; 7055 (Box 43, Folder 14)
  - Lanier, Lyle, 1981; 7056 (Box 43, Folder 15)
  - Maciag, Robert, 1981 April-September; 1977 (Box 43, Folder 16)
  - Mark, Herman, 1981-1990; 7057 (Box 43, Folder 17)
  - Newman, Jeff, 1981 October-1982 February; 1978 (Box 43, Folder 18)
  - Rafsky, Robert, 1983 June-1984 January; 1979 (Box 43, Folder 19)
  - Radley, Melanie, 1983 May-October; 1980 (Box 43, Folder 20)
  - Letters from Significant People, 1966-1967; 7058 (Box 43, Folder 21)
  - Technology and Society and Polytechnic, 1975; 7059 (Box 43, Folder 22)
  - Taiwan Trip, 1975; 7060 (Box 43, Folder 23)
  - Supportive Comments, 1989-1992; 7061 (Box 43, Folder 24)
  - Lamme Nomination, 1990; 7062 (Box 43, Folder 25)
  - Miscellaneous, 1953, 7063 (Box 43, Folder 26)
  - Miscellaneous, 1966, 7064 (Box 43, Folder 27)
  - Miscellaneous, 1967, 7066 (Box 43, Folder 28)
  - Miscellaneous, 1968, 7065 (Box 43, Folder 29)
  - Miscellaneous, 1969, 7068 (Box 43, Folder 30)
  - Miscellaneous, 1970, 7069 (Box 43, Folder 31)
  - Miscellaneous, 1971, 7067 (Box 43, Folder 32)
  - Miscellaneous, 1972, 7070 (Box 43, Folder 33)
  - Miscellaneous, 1973, 7071 (Box 43, Folder 34)
  - Miscellaneous, 1974, 7072 (Box 43, Folder 35)
  - Miscellaneous, 1975, 7073 (Box 43, Folder 36)
  - Miscellaneous, 1976, 7074 (Box 43, Folder 37)
  - Miscellaneous, 1977, 7075 (Box 43, Folder 38)
  - Miscellaneous, 1978, 7076 (Box 43, Folder 39)
  - Miscellaneous, 1979, 7077 (Box 43, Folder 40)
  - Miscellaneous, 1980, 7078 (Box 43, Folder 41)
  - Miscellaneous, 1981, 7079 (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous, 1982, 7080 (Box 44, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous, 1983, 7081 (Box 44, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous, 1984, 7082 (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous, 1985, 7083 (Box 44, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous, 1986, 7084 (Box 44, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous, 1987, 7085 (Box 44, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous, 1988, 7086 (Box 44, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous, 1989, 7087 (Box 44, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous, 1990, 7088 (Box 44, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous, January- March 1991, 1991 January- March; 7089 (Box 44, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous, April - June 1991, 1991 April - June; 7091 (Box 44, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous, July - December 1991, 1991 July - December; 7090 (Box 44, Folder 13)
  - Miscellaneous, January - April 1992, 1992 January - April; 1982 (Box 44, Folder 14)
  - Miscellaneous, May - December 1992, 1992 May- December; 1983 (Box 44, Folder 15)
  - Miscellaneous, January - March 1993, 1993 January-March; 1984 (Box 44, Folder 16)
  - Miscellaneous, April - August 1993, 1993 April-August; 1985 (Box 44, Folder 17)
  - Miscellaneous, September - November 1993, 1993 September-November; 1986 (Box 44, Folder 18)
  - Miscellaneous, December 1993, 1993 December; 1987 (Box 44, Folder 19)
  - Miscellaneous, January - February 1994, 1994 January - February; 7092 (Box 44, Folder 20)
  - Miscellaneous, March - May 1994, 1994 March - May; 7093 (Box 44, Folder 21)
  - Miscellaneous, June - December 1994, 1994 June - December; 7094 (Box 44, Folder 22)
  - Miscellaneous, 1995, 7095 (Box 44, Folder 23)
  - Miscellaneous, 1996, 7096 (Box 44, Folder 24)
  - Miscellaneous, 1997, 7097 (Box 44, Folder 25)
  - Miscellaneous, 1998, 7098 (Box 44, Folder 26)
  - MIscellaneous, 1999-2000, 7140 (Box 44, Folder 27)
  - Miscellaneous, Undated, 7099 (Box 44, Folder 28)
  - Letters of Recommendation – RESTRICT, 1993 March; 1990 (Box 44.1, Folder 1)
  - "W" Correspondence, 1990-1992; 5766 (Box 44.1, Folder 2)
  - "W" Correspondence, 1990-1992; 5767 (Box 44.1, Folder 3)
  - Invitations, 1975-1991, 7101 (Box 44.1, Folder 4)
  - Invitations, 1992-1998; Undated, 7102 (Box 44.1, Folder 5)
  - Business Cards - Loose, undated; 7100 (Box 44.1, Folder 6)
  - Business Cards – Scrapbook, 1981 November-1984 April; 1991 (Box 44.1, Folder 7)
  - Business Cards – Scrapbook, 1986 December; 1992 (Box 44.1, Folder 8)
- Series VIII: Clippings, 1972-1996; 1993
  This series is arranged alphabetically by folder title with the excpetion of folders of miscellaneous publications which are arranged chronologically at the end of the series.
  This series contains local, regional and national newspaper and magazine clippings that mention George Bugliarello, Polytechnic, MetroTech or and other topics in engineering and engineering education.
  - Bioengineering, 1972-1992; 1994 (Box 44.1, Folder 9)
  - Brooklyn - Atlantic Terminal Rehab, 1984-1985; 1997 (Box 44.1, Folder 10)
  - Brooklyn Development, 1983August-1985 August; 1995 (Box 44.1, Folder 11)
  - George Bugliarello, 1978-1992; 1996 (Box 44.1, Folder 12)
  - Brooklyn Newspapers, 1990-1993; 2102 (Box 44.1, Folder 13)
  - Brooklyn Newspapers, 1994; 2103 (Box 44.1, Folder 14)
  - Brooklyn Newspapers, 1995; 2104 (Box 44.1, Folder 15)
  - Brooklyn Newspapers, 1996; 2105 (Box 44.1, Folder 16)
  - Long Island Papers - Farmingdale, 1993-1996; 2106 (Box 44.1, Folder 17)
  - Long Island Business News, 1995 January-April; 2107 (Box 44.1, Folder 18)
  - Long Island Business News, 1996 January-October; 2108 (Box 44.1, Folder 19)
  - New York Newsday, 1992-1996; 2109 (Box 44.1, Folder 20)
  - New York and New Jersey Newspapers, 1975-1991; 7143 (Box 44.1, Folder 21)
  - Westchester, 1992 November-1994 June; 2110 (Box 44.1, Folder 22)
  - Westchester, 1994 July-1996 November; 2111 (Box 44.1, Folder 23)
  - Polytechnic University - Miscellaneous, 1992-1994; 2112 (Box 44.1, Folder 24)
  - Polytechnic University - Miscellaneous, 1995; 2113 (Box 44.1, Folder 25)
  - Polytechnic University - Miscellaneous, 1996 January-May; 2114 (Box 44.1, Folder 26)
  - Polytechnic University - Miscellaneous, 1996 June-December; 2115 (Box 44.1, Folder 27)
  - Italian Newspapers, 1989-1991; 7141 (Box 44.1, Folder 28)
  - Miscellaneous, 1967-2011, undated; 7142 (Box 44.1, Folder 29)
- Series IX: Photographs, 5720; 0 Linear Feet
  Arrangement
  Photographs are arranged into two boxes by size: 4"x6" and smaller are in Box 45 and photographs larger than 4"x6" are in Box 46.
  - Dibner Library Construction, 1990-1992; 962 (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - Dibner Library Construction, 1990-1992; 963 (Box 45, Folder 2)
  - Dibner Library Construction, 1990-1992; 964 (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - Dibner Library Construction, 1990-1992; 965 (Box 45, Folder 4)
  - Dibner Library Construction, 1990-1992; 966 (Box 45, Folder 5)
  - Dibner Library Construction, 1990-1992; 967 (Box 45, Folder 6)
  - Dibner Library Construction - Photographs, 1990-1992; 968 (Box 45, Folder 7)
  - Dibner Library Construction - Photographs, 1990-1992; 969 (Box 45, Folder 8)
  - George Bugliarello - Commencement and Dibner Library, 1992; 7039 (Box 45, Folder 9)